Anming Gu

CONTACT INFORMATION gu.anming106@gmail.com anminggu.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS Foundations of Machine Learning, Algorithms and Theory of Computation, Optimization, Stochastic Calculus, Optimal Transport

I enjoy applying tools in theoretical computer science (e.g. Boolean Fourier analysis, pseudorandomness, and complexity theory) and mathematics (optimization, stochastic calculus, and analysis) to prove theoretical results on machine learning algorithms and architectures.

EDUCATION

Boston University

Boston, MA

B.A. in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics

Expected May 2024

GPA: 3.96/4.00

HONORS AND AWARDS Putnam Math Competition Top 35%

2022

2019

3x AIME Qualifier 2017, 2019, 2020

USA Biology Olympiad Top 30 2020

4x USA Biology Olympiad Semifinalist 2017 – 2020

British Biology Olympiad Gold Medal 2019, 2020

University of Toronto Biology Competition International 18th Place

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Chien Lab, Boston University

Research Assistant, supervised by Prof. Edward Chien

Boston, MA Sept 2020 – Present

- Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program (Spring 2021, Fall 2021), Honors Thesis I &
- II (Expected Fall 2023, Spring 2024).Optimal transport and spectral graph theory for k-mixup regularization in deep learning.
- Optimal transport, stochastic calculus, and mean-field Langevin dynamics for trajectory inference of probability distributions and particle filters.

Independent Research

Boston, MA

Primary Researcher

March 2023 - Present

• Bernstein polynomial approximation, real analysis, topology, and probability theory for Fourier analysis of Boolean functions.

PUBLICATIONS

Manuscripts

K. Greenewald, A. Gu, M. Yurochkin, J. Solomon, E. Chien. k-Mixup Regularization for Deep Learning via Optimal Transport. arXiv preprint: arXiv:2106.02933.

PRESENTATIONS

k-Mixup Regularization for Deep Learning via Optimal Transport

Boston University SIAM, March 2023

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

American Option Pricing via Particle Filters

Created American option pricing algorithms in Python under stochastic volatility and jump-diffusion models using Monte Carlo simulation and particle filters, (Financial Econometrics, Spring 2023).

λ -Calculus Compiler

Wrote a type-checker and compiler for a λ -calculus language to the C language, (Functional

Compilers, Fall 2022).

Monte Carlo Geometry Processing

Implemented Monte Carlo algorithms in C++ to solve linear elliptic PDEs on triangle meshes following the paper [Monte Carlo Geometry Processing: A Grid-Free Approach to PDE-Based Methods on Volumetric Domains], (Geometry Processing, Spring 2022).

Hypergraph Expanders from Cayley Graphs

Explored spectral graph theory and expander graphs in the context of hypergraphs. Wrote an exposition on the paper [Hypergraph expanders of all uniformities from Cayley graphs], (Mathematical Methods for Theoretical Computer Science, Spring 2022).

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Boston University

Boston, MA

- Teaching Assistant: Analysis of Algorithms (Spring 2022)
- Grader: Analysis of Algorithms, Linear Algebra, Honors Differential Equations, Calculus II (Fall 2021)

Industry
EXPERIENCE

Amazon

Sunnyvale, CA

Software Development Intern

Summer 2023

Capital One

Software Engineering Intern

McLean, VA Summer 2022

SKILLS

- Languages: Python, C/C++, OCaml, Java, Bash, MATLAB
- Technologies: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, Jupyter Notebook
- Other: Linux, Git/Github, LATEX, Make

GRADUATE COURSEWORK

- Upcoming: Complexity Theory, Stochastic Calculus, Game Theory
- Theory: An Algorithmist's Toolbox
- ML/AI: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning
- Software: Functional Compilers
- Applications: Geometry Processing
- Pure Mathematics: Functional Analysis
- Economics & Finance: Financial Econometrics

2 Last updated: May 2023